So let's fetch ingredients asynchronously.
yleyse malzemeleri ezamansz olarak getirelim.
I'll do that in the burger builder file in the actions folder where we have our action creators. I'll
Bunu hamburger kasesinde yapacam veya aksiyon yaratclarmzn hepsinin yeni bir aksiyon yaratcs
add a new action creator
ekledii eylemler klasrne deceim.
so I'll export a new const and I'll name it fetchIngredients or maybe better name, initIngredients
Bu yzden yeni bir Konst verin ve ierii getirmek veya belki de bir isim eklemek iin ad vereceim.
because we want to do this initially to load the ingredients we can use in the burger builder.
indekiler balangta bunu yapmak istediin iin ierii yklemek iin Newberger Boler kullanabilirsiniz.
I don't expect any arguments on this function and I want to of course return an action ultimately, though
Bu ileve herhangi bir argman beklemiyorum ve elbette kesin olmak iin sonuta bir eylem
to be precise
dndrmek istiyorum.
I want to return a function here where I receive the dispatch function which I then can use in this
ilev gvdesinde kullanabileceim gnderme ilevini aldm bir ileve geri dnmek istiyorum.
function body
Burada, bu
and this is available, the syntax due to redux-thunk
Ve bu, X funk'u okumak iin szdizimi ina etmenin bir yoludur.
which allows me to use my action creators like this.
Bu da Aksiyonum Creative' kullanmam salyor.
Now in here, I can execute async code and dispatch a new action whenever I'm done,
imdi burada async kodu uygulayabilir ve bittiinde yeni bir eylem gnderebilirim.
so I actually need a second action creator which I'll export to though theoretically, I only use it internally
Aslnda teorik olarak ie aktarrken kullanacam ikinci bir aksiyon yaratcsna ihtiyacm
in this file, I'll name this action creator setIngredients. Here,
var ve bu sonbaharda bu gerek yaratc set malzemelerini buraya yazacam.
I expect to get ingredients as an argument and here, I will just return an action I want to dispatch.
Malzemeleri bir argman olarak almay umuyor ve burada gndermek istediim bir eylemi geri getireceim.
Now for that, I need an action type
imdi bunun iin eylem trne ihtiyacm var.
so let's head over to action types and let's add a new action type here,
imdi harekete geirme trlerine geelim ve burada yeni bir eylem tr ekleyelim.
I'll name it SET_INGREDIENTS and as often or as always,
Altl izen maddeleri ve sklkta ya da her zaman olduu gibi koyacam.
I'll use this as the string identifier too. So SET_INGREDIENTS, that is the identifier
Tanmlayc olan bileenleri ayarlamak iin bunu dize tanmlaycs olarak kullanacam.
I'll listen to it in my reducer later.
Bunu daha sonra redktrmde dinleyeceim.
And with that added, I can go back to the burger builder action file and in the setIngredients action
Ve eklenen burger ektirme eylem dosyasna geri dnebilir ve daha sonra sz
creator, I want to return an object where the type is actionTypes.setIngredients, just like that
edilen katk maddeleri ection yaratcs tr olduu eylem trn ayarlayan bir nesne dndrmek isterim.
and of course, I'll need to pass a payload, I'll name the property ingredients and that name is totally up to you.
Ve tabii ki adlandrlm mlk bileenleri bir yk gemek iin ve bu ad tamamen size kalm.
The value is not, the value should be our function argument
Deeri deer ilev argman olmamaldr.
which here is also named ingredients,
Alternatif malzemeler hangi yldr.
this one. With that, we get the synchronous action creator,
Bunu bir ezamanl eylem yaratcs alp yaparz.
that is the action I eventually want to dispatch once the async code in initIngredients is done.
Init ieriklerindeki async kodu bittikten sonra nihayetinde gndermek istediim eylem budur.
Let's head over to the burger builder container to fetch the async code we want to execute, this thing
Bu ii burada yapmak istediiniz asenk kodu getirmek iin Bergere bullet konteynerine
here.
gidelim.
So I'll just cut it out of the componentDidMount function there and I'll put it into my burger builder
ve ilevi oradan kesip, buradaki eylemler klasrndeki Bergere Boulder dosyasna koyacam elbette yalnzca X'e
file in the actions folder. Here I want to return to axios and for that, I of course need to be able
erimek ve yalnzca u andaki eriim noktasna eriebilmek iin bunu ileri gtrmek istiyorum.
to access axios. Now in the burger builder component, we imported axios from axios orders, we don't need that
Broga Boulder'da artk ihtiya duymadmz exes siparilerinden exes ithal ettiimiz burger Bolar bileeni.
anymore in the burger builder
Bu yzden bileen
so I can cut it from there and also move that import to the burger builder action file. There,
Bu yzden oradan kesebilirim ve ayn zamanda ithalat Bergere cesur eylem dosyasna tayabilirim.
I need to reach out to axios orders,
Emirlere erimek iin uzlamam lazm.
I need to check if my path is correct, it actually is
Potthast'mn doru olduunu kontrol etmem gerekiyor.
so that's all right
Bu yzden her ey yolunda
and now we can reach out to axios in this file too. Here, the path to firebase should still be correct
Ve imdi erimek iin uzlaabiliriz ve bu de burada ate br yolu doru olmal.
but then of course when we get the response, I won't call this.setState and I won't do it for getting
Ancak elbette yant aldmzda bu zc durumu aramayacam ve bir hata elde etmek
an error.
iin yapmayacam.
Instead here, I want to dispatch my setIngredients action creator
Bunun yerine, burada bahsedilen bileenlerin eylem yaratcs gndermek istiyorum.
so here, I'll execute this as a function and of course, I will dispatch response data here on an axios
Yani burada bunu bir ilev olarak yrteceim ve elbette, veri mlkiyetinde kullanmak istediiniz javascript nesnesi olacak
response, the data property holds the data which will be the javascript object we want to use.
verileri barndran gerek bir yant zerinde yant verisini gnderirim.
Now when an error occurs, we probably also want to handle that, in the burger builder container,
imdi bir hata olutuunda, muhtemelen de burger kabnda veya konteynrdaki borla ilgilenmek istiyoruz.
we have that error state, we have the loading state and all these things were used here
Bu hataya sahibiz, devlete yklememiz gereken bir durum var ve btn bunlar burada kullanlyordu.
so I can get rid of error and loading in my burger builder now because I won't manage these state fields
Bu yzden hatadan kurtulabilir ve burger Boulder'a ykleme yapabilirim, nk burada durum alanlarm artk
here in that file anymore.
km durumda kullanmay baaramayacam.
Now loading was only used to show a spinner in the order summary in case we're still loading,
imdi ykleme, yalnzca, hala ykl olmas halinde, sipari zetinde bir eitici gstermek iin kullanld.
this however shouldn't be required here anymore because we're not doing anything asynchronous when viewing
Bununla birlikte artk burada gerekli olmamal nk sipari zetini grntlerken hareket etmeyi
the modal, when viewing the order summary
grntlerken ezamansz bir ey yapmyoruz.
therefore. What is important though is the order, here
Bu nedenle buradaki dzen nemlidir.
we set our burger equal to ingredients can't be loaded if we have an error
Bir hatamz varsa malzememize eit bizim burger yklenemedi dedik.
and to a spinner if we don't
Ve yapmazsak bir eirmene.
and we actually set it to a real burger builder
Ve aslnda onu gerek bir burger bowlingisine ayarladk.
if props have been loaded.
Pervane ykl olursa.
So we definitely need to set this error, though not on a state anymore,
Dolaysyla bu hatay artk bir devlette deil de olsa ayarlamalyz.
we want to pass it with props.
Sahne ile geirmek istiyoruz.
So for that, I need to handle this error as part of my redux state, for that, I'll go to my burger builder
Bor iin bu hatay Rydex eyaletinin bir paras olarak ele almam gerekiyor, nk burger redktr
reducer
ekip gideceim.
and here, I'll first of all set ingredients to null initially because now we're fetching them from the web
Ve burada ilk balarda boa maddeler syleniyordu, nk imdi onlar tekrar
again and they should be null until they were fetched,
web'den getiriyoruz ve getirilene kadar olmamalyd.
that is all that's required to make sure that this check here in the burger builder fails
Burger Boulder'daki bu kontroln baarsz olmasna dikkat etmeleri gerekiyor.
if we don't have ingredients yet so that we do display a spinner instead.
Henz ieriine sahip deilsek, bunun yerine bir eirici grntleriz.
But I also need to add a new state to my burger builder state, I'll name it
Ama ayn zamanda burger kaseye yeni bir devlet eklemem lazm ya da durumun hepsini belirtmeliyim.
error and here, I'll set this to false
Ve burada Utset a'ya geti.
initially, I want to set it to true though if our loading does fail. With that added, we need one more
Balangta yklemem baarsz olursa olsa da True olarak ayarlamak istiyorum Eklenen e ile bir daha eyleme
action though,
ihtiyacm var.
back to the burger builder file in the actions folder, we dispatch an action if we got ingredients that's
Hareketli bir madde gnderdiysek, bir eylem gnderdiimiz eylemler klasrn izleyerek burger ekiciye
great but we also need to dispatch an action
geri dndmzde, harika bir eylem gndermemiz gerekiyor.
if that fails so that we can adjust our error state in the redux state. So I'll add a new action type
Bu baarsz olursa hava veya durumumuzu redksiyon durumuna gre ayarlayabilir veya yeni bir eylem tr
and I'll name it FETCH_INGREDIENTS_FAILED and use the same name as the string identifier
ekleyebiliriz ve ierii getirip baarsz hale getireceimizi ve dize tanmlaycsyla ayn ad kullanacamz syleyeceim.
as always and then I'll add an action creator here.
Her zamanki gibi, burada aksiyon yaratcs ekleyeceim.
We not only have setIngredients, I also want to have fetchIngredientsFailed here,
Sadece hazrlanm ieriklerime sahip deil, ayn zamanda ierii baarsz olmasn istiyorum.
I won't get an error message so I don't need to accept any argument,
Herhangi bir argman kabul etmem iin bir hata mesaj almayacam.
I just want to return a javascript object here where the type is actionTypes and then FETCH_INGREDIENTS_
Sadece burada bir tr javascript nesnesi dndrmek istiyorum, burada eylem trleri ve sonra ierii gibi
FAILED, like this
baarsz getirmek getirmek.
and this is the action I actually want to dispatch when it fails.
Ve baarsz olduunda aslnda gndermek istediim eylem budur.
So I'll dispatch something in the error case too, I'll dispatch fetchIngredientsFailed and don't pass
Dolaysyla, tm bu yama, hata durumundaki tm bu yamalarn ierii getiren bir ey baarsz oldu ve herhangi
any arguments.
bir argman kabul etmiyor.
So with that I'm handling both cases and
Bu yzden her iki davay da hallediyorum.
now of course, we need to handle these new actions in the reducer and also make sure that we connect
imdi tabii ki bu yeni eylemleri redktrde ele almamz gerekiyor ve ayn zamanda Berger boucumuzu,
our burger builder correctly to these new things like for example, the error state and one thing I just
rnein hata durumu ve burger Boler konteynrnda eriime ihtiya duyduumuzun fark ettii bir ey
noticed, we also still need axios in the burger builder container for this withErrorHandler
gibi yeni eylere doru ekilde baladmzdan emin olmalyz. hata ileyicisi olan disk iin.
higher order component.
Yksek sipari bileeni.
So I'll quickly grab that axios import from the burger builder action file again and re-add it to the
Bu yzden, burger Boler eylem dosyasndan bu eriimi hzl bir ekilde alp yeniden
burger builder container.
burger Boler konteynrna ekleyeceim.
Now one important note about that, we can still handle the errors with our higher order component here
oklar ileyebileceimiz konusunda nemli bir not, gerek bir rnei kullandmzdan isteimizi, uyuturucu
because we're using an axios instance, so no matter if we do send the request from another place in the app
eylemi oluturucusu gibi baka bir yerdeki NEAP adresinden gnderirsek de yapalm.
like our async action creator,
Artk yksek sipari bileenimizle
we can still handle it with the same axios instance which we're passing to the higher order component to
Hl aero modelimizi gstermek iin yksek mertebeden bileene repassing eden ayn eriim
show our error modal
rneiyle yk atabiliriz.
which of course is what we want to do
Elbette ki ne yapmak istiyorsun.
still, we want to have this central error handling place.
Hala merkezi hata ileme yerimiz olsun istiyoruz.
Now with all that in place though, our application wouldn't work as expected because now we need to work
imdi her ey dahil olsa da, uygulamanz beklendii gibi almyor nk imdi bu yeni eylem
on the reducer to handle these new action types
trlerini ilemek iin klte zerinde almaya ihtiyacmz var.
we have for fetching ingredients.
Malzemeleri getirmek zorundayz.
Right now, it's always spinning.
u anda her zaman dnyor.